relevantid.com 2010-01-26

# RELEVANTID - PRIVACY POLICY

|   
---  
| 

**What is RelevantID®?**

RelevantID is a technology utilized by RelevantView **®** that works through a combination of watermarking and digital fingerprint technology to enable RelevantView to improve the quality and integrity of survey results for its customers (“ _ _Users__ ”). Digital fingerprinting is the process of collecting data points from the web browser of a respondent’s computer to create a unique identifier. 

RelevantID does not download any software onto a respondent’s computer. RelevantID does not track the online activities of a respondent. 

RelevantID obtains the _Collected Infor_ mation (as defined herein) from a respondent’s computer when the respondent joins a survey panel, starts a survey or participates in a marketing campaign.

**Information Collected In Connection with RelevantID**

RelevantID does not collect any personally identifiable information ( _“_ _ _PII__ ”) concerning the owner or user of a computer (though we do collect the publicly available IP address, which may be considered _PII_ in some non-US jurisdictions). RelevantID collects publicly available information from within the web browser of a respondent computer. This publicly available information may include, without limitation, the operating system version, the browser version, screen resolution, and display information (the “ _ _Collected Information__ ”).    **__**

**Uses of Collected Information**

_Collected Information_ is processed through RelevantID’s proprietary algorithm to create a digital fingerprint that is assigned to a respondent’s computer. _Collected Information_ is used solely to confirm the unique presence of a respondent’s computer. _Collected Information_ is used only in connection with RelevantID and is not used, transferred, sold or distributed for any other purpose(s).

Generally, RelevantID is used for de-duping purposes, to perform respondent quality assessments, and redirect detection and prevention services. In the event that a _User_ provides RelevantView with a respondent ID, RelevantView can match the respondent ID to the RelevantID. After matching the respondent ID and RelevantID, RelevantView will provide the matched IDs to the _User_ , either in a database or some other form or format as requested by the _User_. At no time does RelevantView receive or have access to any _PII_ connected to the respondent IDs. 

**Disclosure of Collected Information**

The RelevantID and the _Collected Information_ are disclosed only to the _User_ and its authorized employees and/or agents.  

**Disclaimer**

RelevantView hereby disclaims any and all liability and/or responsibility for the privacy practices of _Users_. RelevantView strongly recommends that respondents refer to the _User_ and/or the User’s website(s) for information on the privacy practices applicable to the appropriate _User_. RelevantView does not review, comment upon, or monitor its Users’ compliance with their respective privacy policies.

**Disclosures**

RelevantView will use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that RelevantID is safe, secure and does not cause undue privacy or data security risks. 

In the event that RelevantView discovers or learns of any unethical conduct in connection with the use of RelevantID or that RelevantID is being used in a manner inconsistent with this RelevantID Privacy Policy; and/or (i) any applicable international, Federal, state and/or local laws, codes, regulations, rules and/or requirements and/or (ii) codes and regulations of the trade and/or professional association(s) and/or organization(s) with whom RelevantView is a member, including without limitation the Council of American Survey Research Organizations, RelevantView will use its best efforts to correct, rectify, and prohibit such unethical conduct and to ensure the proper administration of RelevantID. 

**RelevantView Privacy Policy**

This RelevantID Privacy Policy supplements the RelevantView Privacy Policy, located at <http://www.relevantview.com/privacy.htm>. This RelevantID Privacy Policy and the RelevantView Privacy Policy should be reviewed for a complete understanding of the privacy policies, practices and procedures followed by RelevantView. 

**Contacting Us**

If you have questions regarding our Privacy Statement, please contact us at [info@relevantview.com](mailto:info@relevantview.com)

The foregoing policies are effective as of February 1, 2009. RelevantView reserves the right to change this policy at any time. This statement and the policies outlined herein are not intended to and do not create any contractual or other legal rights in or on behalf of any party.

|
